<sect1 id="microsoft.windowsazure">
    <title>Microsoft_WindowsAzure</title>

    <sect2 id="microsoft.windowsazure.introduction">
        <title>Introduction</title>

        <para>
          Windows Azure is the name for Microsoft’s Software + Services platform,
          an operating system in the cloud providing services for hosting, management,
          scalable storage with support for simple blobs, tables, and queues,
          as well as a management infrastructure for provisioning and geo-distribution
          of cloud-based services, and a development platform for the Azure Services layer.
        </para>
    </sect2>

  <sect2 id="microsoft.windowsazure.sdk">
    <title>Installing the Windows Azure SDK</title>

    <para>
      There are two development scenario's when working with Windows Azure.

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can develop your application using <code>Microsoft_WindowsAzure</code>
            and the Windows Azure SDK, which provides a local developent environment
            of the services provided by Windows Azure's cloud infrastructure.
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can develop your application using <code>Microsoft_WindowsAzure</code>,
            working directly with the Windows Azure cloud infrastructure.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <para>
      The first case requires you to install the <ulink url="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=11B451C4-7A7B-4537-A769-E1D157BAD8C6&amp;displaylang=en">Windows Azure SDK</ulink> on your development machine.
      It is currently only available for Windows environments, progress is being made on a Java-based version of the
      SDK which can run on any platform.
    </para>

    <para>
      The latter case requires you to have an account at <ulink url="http://www.azure.com">Azure.com</ulink>.
    </para>
  </sect2>

    <sect2 id="microsoft.windowsazure.apiDocumentation">
        <title>API Documentation</title>

        <para>
            The <code>Microsoft_WindowsAzure</code> class provides the PHP wrapper to the
            Windows Azure REST interface. Please consult the 
            <ulink url="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/dd179355.aspx">REST documentation</ulink> 
            for detailed description of the service. You will need to be familiar with basic concepts
            in order to use this service.
        </para>
    
    </sect2>

  <sect2 id="microsoft.windowsazure.features">
    <title>Features</title>

    <para>
      <code>Microsoft_WindowsAzure</code> provides the following functionality:

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            PHP classes for Windows Azure Blobs, Tables and Queues (for CRUD operations)
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            Helper Classes for HTTP transport, AuthN/AuthZ, REST and Error Management
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            Manageability, Instrumentation and Logging support
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="microsoft.windowsazure.architecture">
    <title>Architecture</title>

    <para>
      <code>Microsoft_WindowsAzure</code> provides access to Windows Azure's storage,
      computation and management interfaces by abstracting the REST/XML interface
      Windows Azure provides into a simple PHP API.
    </para>

    <para>
      An application built using <code>Microsoft_WindowsAzure</code> can access Windows Azure's
      features, no matter if it is hosted on the Windows Azure platform or on
      an in-premise web server.
    </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
